It's 10.30,
so we'll get started.
Good to see everyone again.
I'd like to thank you for
choosing to come to class
instead of the career fair.
I see the Google line is
blocking our room.
I came up five minutes before
and I saw the United Airlines
booth and I was trying to get a
keychain from them, but then I
think they thought I was a
student trying to come to mine,
so I was like,
let's go to class,
but we'll go try and get a
keychain after.
Announcements.
Homework 2 is due on Friday.
I have office hours after
lecture, as usual, so we can
chat about it.
And you should see your Homework
1 scores available on Pensyf.
So make sure to take a look at
those and also review the
solutions.
As I mentioned in the post in
which I released the grades on
Ed,
as it talks about in the
syllabus and I think we've
mentioned before,
Pensyf uses AI to do some
grading.
But I don't want people to get
the impression that we just give
ChatGPT your homework and say
grade it.
That's not how it works.
Instead,
we humans create rubrics for
every question.
And they're actually the same
rubrics we used to use when we
used Gradescope.
So if you're familiar with how
Gradescope-based grading worked
in like 203 or, I don't know,
math classes, things like that,
it's the same setup using the
same rubrics.
And so how it works is we give
the rubrics to pensive.
And then what it does
independently for every question
is it tries to transcribe what
you wrote into text and LaTeX.
So it tries to convert your
formulas into typed formulas.
And then it takes that
conversion and a screenshot of
what you wrote and our rubrics,
and it tries to assign rubric
items as best as it can.
If it's confident in its ability
to do that, and that's measured
by asking several different
LLMs,
hey,
what rubric items should we
pick? If they all agree,
then that's probably the right
combination of rubric items, and
so that's what it assigns.
But if they don't all agree,
then it flags it for our graders
to have to go in and manually
grade it ourselves.
And so I'd say about 20% of
submissions
had to be manually graded that
way and then on top of that we
like spot checked various
questions to make sure that that
grading was done correctly and
then on top of that if you think
something didn't get graded
correctly there's always the
ability to submit a regrade
request as there was on grade
scope so I just want you to have
faith in the system and it's not
just that we're telling chat to
give you a random number that's
not how it works it works the
same way as it did on grade
scope but as you see we can turn
around grades way quicker than
you we could in other classes
right Homework one was just due
this past Friday, and normally
would take at least a week to
grade.
And then lastly,
as you may have seen on ed
several times this past week,
there have been various events
in the atrium.
So the TA's office hours
locations may change.
I think if they have office
hours later today, that may also
be the case because of the
career fair.
But my office hours are in my
office either way.
The plan for today is to start
by recapping some key elements
of the simple linear regression
model, which was our main
objective of study last week.
There was one tie-in to it that
I wanted to talk about on
Thursday that I didn't get to,
which was the correlation
coefficient.
So we will look at that.
And then we will motivate the
need
for introducing linear algebra,
which we have not yet used in
this class.
But that will change today.
But before I introduce what a
vector is and what various
properties of it are,
we're going to make sure we have
a clear understanding of why
that is absolutely necessary to
progress
our point in the story of this
course.
OK,
so here's what I want to start
with.
Over the past few weeks,
we've been using this running
example data set in which we
wanted to predict how long it
would take for us to get to
work.
That's the commute time on the
y-axis of this graph, given the
time we left in the morning.
That's the departure time on the
x-axis of this graph.
And we've studied two models or
types of functions that we could
use for this task.
The first was the constant
model.
And so the type of question we
asked was, well,
if the constant model is a flat
line,
what is the best place to draw
that flat line? And the answer
depends on which loss function
we use to measure the quality of
our predictions.
If we use the squared loss loss
function, then we choose the
constant parameter W that
minimizes average squared loss
or mean squared error.
And as you now know, that is the
mean or average of the y's.
If you use absolute loss, Well,
then you end up with a different
best parameter the median of the
lies,
okay So that's the kind of
thinking we use in the first few
lectures and then last lecture
We said well, what if we don't
just use a flat constant model?
But instead we have a simple
linear regression line one that
is allowed to have two
parameters a slope and an
intercept Then the question is
well, what is the best
combination of slope and
intercept to use again? It
depends on the last function you
use if you use squared loss
Well, then you end up with the
formulas as we saw last class.
If you use absolute loss,
well, there's no closed form
formula for the best intercept
and slope.
But if you've taken a look at
the programming question in
homework two,
there we have you implement some
code that allows you to find the
best slope and intercept for
absolute loss in the simple
linear regression model.
A sort of side question I wanted
to address here
is these two lines intersect at
a point.
What are the coordinates of that
point these intersect at?
Assuming we used squared loss
for both,
to find both,
what point do these two
intersect at?
Gavin?
Is it x-bar or y-bar?
Yeah, it is.
Why is that?
Assuming we use squared loss,
y is the point at which these
two lines intersect,
the average departure time,
that's x bar,
comma,
the average commute time in our
data set,
y bar.
Why is that?
Anyone know?
Any guesses?
Why is this intersection mean of
x comma mean of y?
One of the two coordinates of
this intersection is easier to
reason about than the other.
Why do we know for sure that
they intersect at a point where
the y-coordinate is y-bar?
This one doesn't require that
much.
Stop.
In a constant model,
we know w star is going to be
the mean.
Exactly.
We know that this line is being
drawn,
essentially, at y equals y-bar,
or the output equals y-bar.
So if this line hits this one,
well, the only possible y-axis
value of this line is y-bar.
So at this intersection,
that point must also have a
y-axis value of y bar.
The question is, why is it the
input x bar?
Could have been something else.
Why is the input, or the
x-coordinate of this
intersection x bar?
Why is that?
Anyone have an idea why is the
input or why is the x-coordinate
of this intersection the mean of
the x?
Well, let's suppose we didn't
know what the x-axis coordinate
of this intersection was.
So how could we figure out what
it would have to be?
Well,
let's take a look at the
formulas.
Remember, our simple linear
regression model looked
something like this,
where the best slope had several
formulas.
And one of the things we
discussed on Thursday was how
you can show these several
formulas are equivalent.
So that's something important to
review.
This was the formula for the
best slope on the numerator.
The sum where i goes from 1 to n
of xi minus x bar times yi minus
y bar.
And on the denominator,
the sum where i goes from 1 to n
of xi minus x bar squared.
And then the intercept was what?
Can someone remind me what the
best intercept is?
Yeah, Kate? y bar minus w1 star
x bar.
Good.
So it turns out that the formula
for the best intercept
actually helps us answer this
mystery from the previous slide,
why these two lines intersect at
x bar comma y bar.
Why is that?
Well,
let's suppose I want
to figure out the height of the
orange line here when I plug in
x bar as an input.
The answer is going to be
something.
It could be y bar.
It could be something else.
Who knows what it is?
But x bar is a legal prediction
to plug in.
And if I use the formulas, it'll
tell me what the the
corresponding prediction should
be.
Do we agree?
So if we can plug in x bar as an
input to this hypothesis
function on the top of the
slide,
w0 plus w1 xi,
based on the assertion we made
on the previous slide, the
output should be y bar.
But if we can show that using a
formula, well, then that will
have proved why this is the
case.
So here's what I'm saying.
h of xi equals w0 plus w1 xi.
But let's call h star xi being
the specific hypothesis function
that uses our best slope and
best intercept.
What I'm saying is,
what if we plug in
x bar?
That is, if I leave at an
average departure time, what is
my predicted commute time?
Are we following?
I could plug in any number I
want.
I could plug in 7, 12, 13,
whatever.
But I'm saying, what if we plug
in the average of the data set
we've already collected?
Well then,
this tells me h star of x bar
is equal to w0 star plus w1 star
x bar.
How can I start to simplify this
to see if there's a more
convenient way of expressing
this output?
Can you plug in a highlighter
for w0?
Exactly.
What I'm going to do is I'm
going to take the formula in the
top right for the best intercept
here and put that here.
So now I'm going to have y bar
minus w1 star x bar
plus w1 star x bar.
And then what do you notice?
What do you notice?
Allison.
Just turns into a y bar.
Yeah,
those cancel out, and you're
left with y bar.
So what this is saying is if you
plug in x bar as an input to
this function, the output comes
out as y bar.
And so this is an important fact
to remember.
The average x comma the average
y always lies on the best simple
linear regression line,
again, when you're using squared
loss to find that line.
If you were using some other
loss function, that property
isn't necessarily true.
So are we clear on why the point
of intersection between these
two lines,
assuming both of them were
chosen to minimize average
squared loss,
is average x comma average y?
OK, yeah, same.
How did we derive y1 prime?
W1 star?
You're talking about this?
That's from Thursday's lecture.
The big idea is that we said we
wanted to
minimize the average squared
loss,
which is the average of actual
minus predicted
squared.
And remember, we said this was a
function of two input variables
or two parameters.
And we call this R.
And so remember on, and there's
a 1 over n because there's an
average.
On Thursday,
we took partial derivatives of
this function with respect to w0
and w1.
And we solved for the w0 and w1,
where the partial derivatives
were both 0.
And when doing that, this is the
formula,
or a formula, for w1 star that
we found.
So that's a good thing to
review.
I think that's in chapter 2.3.
OK,
good.
OK, other questions so far with
simple linear regression?
Team OK?
All right.
Now,
the idea I wanted to wrap up our
discussion of simple linear
regression with is that of the
correlation coefficient.
How many people have heard of a
correlation coefficient before?
Many of you have heard of this.
It's like an idea that if you
took a high school stats class,
it would have come up.
But it turns out that it's
closely related to the simple
linear regression line
that we've seen.
So the correlation coefficient,
this is in chapter 2.4.
is denoted with the letter R,
measures the strength
of the linear,
that's important here,
association between x and
y.
Did someone remind me, if you've
seen this before?
Again, it's totally fine if you
have not.
What are the largest and
smallest possible values of this
thing?
1 and negative 1.
Good.
So no matter the data set,
the correlation coefficient
is between negative 1 and 1.
This is different than mean
squared error, right? Mean
squared error could be
arbitrarily big.
And the units of mean squared
error are the units of y
squared.
So for example,
for these models here,
their mean squared errors will
be in minutes squared, because
the y values are in minutes.
They're commute times in
minutes.
And then their actual minus
predicted y squared.
So the mean squared errors would
be in minutes squared.
The correlation coefficient is
not in any units.
It's just a number that ranges
between negative 1 and 1.
What does positive 1 mean? A 1,
positive 1 means if you drew a
scatter plot of x and y,
the points would lie exactly on
a straight line.
Everything lies exactly on a
straight line.
But in addition to that,
that straight line has a
positive slope.
So I'm doing this, but to me,
that should be drawing this for
you,
positive slope.
A negative 1 correlation means
the points lie exactly on a
straight line with a negative
slope.
Close to 0 means the points
don't look like they lie on a
line at all,
and values in between are, well,
something in between.
So here are some examples.
In this top left one,
it doesn't really seem like
there's a pattern between the
x's and y's.
You could argue that maybe they
fit a circle, but that's not a
line, and so the correlation is
pretty close to 0.
It's very, very, very slightly
positive,
but essentially it's 0.
In the second one, it seems like
the points lie almost exactly on
a straight line, not perfectly,
because there is no line that
passes through all of these.
But it's pretty close to being
the case that all of these
points lie on a negatively
sloped line, which is why the
correlation coefficient is
almost negative 1.
It's negative 0.993.
The bottom left one is the most
confusing,
because there is a very clear
pattern between the x and y.
Like,
obviously, it seems like there's
this absolute value v shape
along which the x's and y's
fall.
But remember, the point is the
correlation coefficient measures
how much it looks like the
scatter plot is one straight
line.
And it doesn't look like that at
all in the bottom left.
There's no one straight line
that would fit this data well.
If you extend to two straight
lines, then maybe.
But that's not what we're asking
here,
which is why the correlation in
the bottom left is very weak as
well.
And because it's slightly
negative,
the formula thinks, and we're
going to look at the formula in
a second, thinks the best
fitting line would be sloped
negatively.
And then the bottom right, it
seems like the points are going
up and to the right, which is
why the correlation coefficient
is positive rather than
negative.
But it's not,
it's positive, but not close to
1, right? It's 0.6,
which means it's up and to the
right, but there's still a lot
of vertical spread.
The trend isn't as clear as it
could be.
Are we OK with this intuitive
understanding of how the
correlation coefficient works?
OK.
Now,
I sort of implicitly said this
here,
but do you agree that it feels
like it should be the case that
if the correlation is positive
between x and y,
then the slope of the best
fitting line should also be
positive?
And if the correlation is
negative,
well, then the slope of the best
fitting line should also be
negative.
Do we agree?
OK.
OK,
so it turns out that there's a
way to express,
and I'll put this two slides in
the future,
the slope of the best fitting
line,
again, assuming we're using
squared loss here.
This is all under the guise that
we're using squared loss.
This slope,
which has many equal forms,
this is just the default one
that I think of.
Lots of other forms.
There's also a way to write it
in terms of the correlation
coefficient,
R.
And I really like this formula
because it's much more concise
than these ones that have
summations in them.
It is the correlation
coefficient
times the standard deviation of
the y values over the standard
deviation of the x-values.
So this right away tells you
that if the correlation is
positive,
the slope is positive.
If the correlation is negative,
the slope is negative.
Why is that?
Well, these standard deviations.
They can't be negative.
So standard deviation of y is
positive, standard deviation of
x is positive.
Can someone remind me, how do
you define the standard
deviation of y? This has come up
in homework one,
but I don't think we directly
discussed it here.
What is the standard deviation
of the y values?
How would I calculate that?
It's the average distance of any
y point from y bar.
It's close to that, but it's
subtly different.
I'm going to start by taking 1
over n times the
sum, where i goes from 1 to n,
of yi minus y bar.
Indeed, it's related to that,
but those distances are supposed
to be squared.
And then the standard deviation
takes the square root of all of
that.
So this is a little different
than the formula you said,
because the average distance
from yi to y bar would not
involve a squared here, but that
would have an absolute value.
And a key algebraic fact we need
to remember here is that this
square root doesn't cancel out
these squares.
The entire average, or this
entire summation, needs to be
evaluated first, and then you
square root the result.
So this is how we define the
standard deviation.
And the thing inside of this
square root here, What is that
called again?
The variance,
which is,
again, something you played
around with in homework one.
So depending on the question
you're working on,
this correlation coefficient
version of the formula may be
more convenient to reason about
the situation,
which is why I think it's useful
to know.
But this, of course,
I sort of skipped a step.
and I told you that there's a
way of expressing the line with
the correlation coefficient,
but I never really told you how
the correlation coefficient was
defined.
Now, if you look at this,
it seems like the correlation
coefficient has to involve some
sort of summation,
because it seems like we're
wrapping a lot of the behavior
of these summations into the
correlation coefficient.
So how do we define the
correlation coefficient?
There is a formula for it, but
then I'll tell you the English
way of interpreting it.
It also involves a 1 over n
times the sum,
where i goes from 1 to n,
of xi minus x bar times
yi minus y bar.
But each of these are divided by
the standard deviations of the
respective variables.
So this is a formula.
And,
well, sure, you could memorize
it.
There's an English way of
interpreting this that you could
say to someone who hasn't taken
this class.
I want you to try and think
creatively of the English way of
saying this.
OK, I'm here.
So how many people here took
EECS 280?
And if you took EECS 280, you
probably went on their website
and went to that grade
calculator thing where you type
in your midterm grade and it
shows you some bell curve.
What was going on there? Like,
how do they implement that?
Jovanita? Z-score?
Yeah.
And how is that related to this?
So he said z-score.
What is a z-score?
Well,
I was going to say,
like,
our needs can multiply into
z-scores together.
Yeah.
The key is that what I'm doing
here
with x and y individually is I'm
converting them to their
z-scores.
So what this is measuring is the
number of standard deviations
xi is above the mean of the x's.
And the second factor here is
the equivalent for the y.
The number of standard
deviations yi is above
y bar.
So with that understanding,
what I'm seeing here is that for
each value in my data set, so I
have my x's all written out and
my y's all written out, and you
should think of each of these as
being points,
what I'm doing is I'm
multiplying what's called the z
score for each coordinate.
So I convert x to its number of
standard deviations above x bar,
and I convert y to its number of
standard deviations above y bar.
So now a positive value means
you're above average, and a
negative value means you're
below average.
Now what I do is I multiply
these z scores for x's,
my x's and my y's, and then I
take their average product.
So it's the average product of
the z scores of x and y.
And another way that z-scores
are sometimes put
are standard units.
So what does a z-score of 2
mean?
What does a z-score of 2 mean?
You're two standard deviations
above the mean?
Yeah,
a z-score of two, no matter what
distribution or variable you're
looking at,
just means the data point you're
looking at is two standard
deviations above its average,
or above the average of the data
set it came from.
And so why these are sometimes
called standard units is that
z-scores don't have any units.
Whereas in our example data set,
The x values are measured in
time.
8.45
was some number of hours.
And the y's were measured in
minutes.
But notice the numerator and
denominator, if we look at just
yi minus y bar over standard
deviation of y,
if we're using our commute times
example, this is in minutes,
and this is also in minutes.
So the units of minutes get
divided out.
And so this doesn't have any
units.
And so the correlation
coefficient is the average
product of x and y once both
columns of this data set have
been converted to z-scores.
Why does this make sense as a
formula for the correlation?
Well, here's roughly one way to
think about it.
What I've done is I've taken an
example data set,
and I've drawn these black bars,
a vertical one at the average x
value and a horizontal one at
the average y value.
So this is average x,
average y.
For a data set in which the
linear association looks
positive, meaning it looks like
it slopes upwards,
you'd expect most of the points
to be in the top right and
bottom left.
Most of the data should be here.
And so the two factors in that
sum we just computed,
this is positive if xi is above
its mean, And this is positive
if yi is above its mean.
So if they're both usually above
their mean together,
or both usually below their mean
together, we're multiplying two
positive numbers, which is
positive,
or two negative numbers, which
is also positive.
So up here is positive times
positive, and down here is
negative times negative.
So if most of the data isn't in
the top right or bottom left,
those products will usually be
positive, which is why the
average of them will be
positive.
If, on the other hand, we had a
negative linear association,
well, then we'd expect most of
the data points to be in the top
left and bottom right.
And if you're in the top left,
well, then if you multiply your
x-coordinate and y-coordinate,
once they've been centered here
by subtracting the mean,
one will be positive, one will
be negative.
Here, the y is above average,
the x is below average.
You multiply those coordinates,
you get a negative number.
And here, it's the opposite.
x is above average, y is below
average.
You multiply those coordinates,
you get a negative number.
So the average of those products
would be negative.
So this is one way to see why
the correlation coefficient has
the definition that it does.
And as I said before,
the correlation coefficient
gives us another way of defining
the slope of the line that
minimizes mean squared error.
OK,
what questions with the
correlation coefficient do we
have?
You seem OK?
One last thing.
Chapter 2.4
has some cool examples at the
bottom that you can play with.
One of them is this data set
called the Anscombs Quartet.
And what it illustrates are four
data sets, that is pairs of x, y
points,
in which the average x value,
average y value,
standard deviation of x and y
and correlation coefficient are
all the same.
If you have just those five
numbers, that tells you what the
slope and intercept of the line
that minimizes mean squared
error is.
Because here, the slope only
depends on the correlation,
the standard deviation of y,
and the standard deviation of x.
And the intercept depends on the
mean of y,
the slope, and the mean of x.
So if I give you the five
numbers I've highlighted here,
r,
standard deviation of x,
standard deviation of y,
mean of x, mean of y,
then you can draw the line of
best fit.
That's all you need.
But what I'm showing you here is
that the data set could look
very different.
Like you could have two very
different looking data sets
that share those five
quantities.
So just like knowing a bunch of
numbers and crunching a bunch of
numbers is not enough,
it's important when you are
working with real data to try
and visualize it as best as you
can.
Because these data sets look
very different, Yet all have the
same best-fitting line.
Okay, and if you go to chapter
2.4
and scroll down, there's an even
cooler example You know, it's
cool enough that we can go look
at it together
Think I included this here.
Yeah, okay Watch these all of
these data sets have those same
five quantities in common
Average X average Y X standard
deviation Y standard deviation
and correlation including one
that looks like a dinosaur
OK?
All of these share those same
five properties, so they all
have the same line of best fit.
And so my bigger picture here is
I don't rely just on numbers to
make all of your decisions.
Just because it is the best
fitting line doesn't mean a line
makes sense to fit the data.
Questions with any of that?
Sound OK?
All right.
So now that we have a good
understanding of the simple
linear regression model,
what I want to comment on is
where we go from here.
So if you remember on the first
day of class,
when I introduced our example
data set in which we were using
a real person's log of their
commutes to work,
we said our goal would be to
predict commute time in minutes.
Those were our y's given the
departure times,
which were the x's.
We used one x to predict our y.
And because we were only using
one input variable,
we were performing what's called
simple linear regression.
But we said, hey,
at some point, it would be nice
if we could learn how to use
multiple input variables or
multiple features.
For example,
it would be cool if we could use
the day of the week,
because it seems like different
days would have different
commute time patterns.
Using day of the week is still a
little tricky because we have to
somehow address the fact that
the days of the week are stored
as words,
and we'd have to convert them to
numbers somehow.
That's a more nuanced issue than
it initially seems, so we will
deal with that later.
But for now, to illustrate how
this could work,
why don't we just pick another
number that is associated with
each data point, which is the
day of the month.
Doesn't necessarily seem like it
would be that useful, but I
don't know.
Maybe commutes at the end of the
month take longer because
they're giving more people
speeding tickets so there's more
traffic on the highway.
I don't know.
Maybe there's a pattern.
Who knows?
So why don't we see what the
resulting hypothesis function
would look like if we also use
day of month,
which I'm going to abbreviate as
DOM.
Now,
what does the formula for our
hyper in a departure hour, I'm
going to abbreviate as DH,
and you'll see why I'm
abbreviating these in just a
second.
What does the resulting
hypothesis function look like
algebraically now?
Well,
I might write something like H
of departure hour i,
comma,
day of month i.
Are we clear on what this
notation means?
I'm writing my hypothesis
function as if it takes in two
input variables.
Every other hypothesis function
we saw so far just took in one
input variable, h of xi.
Now I have two x's, so I
invented new notation to
distinguish between the two x's.
Sound OK?
So this is just a hypothesis
function And that takes in
departure hour and day of
month.
And what do you think the form
for this hypothesis function
will be?
Like what's the most natural
extension of things we've seen
so far?
Yeah, got it.
Can we do w sub 0?
And then w sub 1 d h of 1 of d h
of i.
Yeah, we could do the first
slope times departure hour
i plus?
w sub 2 day of months of i.
Good.
The most natural extension of
the simple linear regression
model is to just tack on another
slope times feature.
So previously, we just had one
slope.
Our model was just this.
One slope, and we called it the
slope,
times xi.
But now we have multiple x's, so
they should each get their own
slope.
And you can imagine here we're
just using two input variables.
So I had two slopes, w1 and w2.
But if I had a third input
variable,
like somehow I figure out how to
use the day of the week, I could
add that in.
I could add another,
you know, like plus W three
times day of the week.
I could add in a plus W four
times how much gas is left in my
car.
Yeah, I could add in all kinds
of things here.
Right, you can start to see how
the number of parameters in a
model grows.
Again,
these parameters, I said this on
the first day of class,
you know, this model now has
three parameters.
The most, you know,
state-of-the-art
large language models have on
the order of a trillion
parameters,
okay, which is why they can
predict and calculate much more
complicated things than this
model that really just predicts
commute time.
But underlying the end product
that you work with is some sort
of formula that looks like a
more complicated version of
this.
Now,
the simple linear regression
model looked like a line.
What does this model look like?
If I had to graph it out,
what's it going to look like?
Gustavo? It'd be like a plane.
Yeah,
what made you come to that
conclusion?
I was just thinking that you'd
have to have an extra dimension.
Exactly.
What we wouldn't.
Like a slope based on which
dimension you're changing.
Exactly.
So I'm going to switch over to
chapter 2.5
where we have an interactive
version of this.
But exactly.
What I want you to imagine is
pretend this classroom
is the xy plane.
Or let's not use x and y.
Let's use departure time and day
of month.
Those are our two input
variables.
And my model should give me a
prediction no matter where I
stand in the classroom,
which is no matter what
combination of departure time
and day of month I pick.
So every point in the classroom
is another combination of
departure time and day of the
month.
And then, based on that,
the height
tells me what the prediction is.
So the original data set itself
is in three dimensions.
Each point here, in blue,
corresponds to one row of the
data set.
So this one that I'm hovering
over here
tells me,
for this one, we left at like 6,
somewhere just after 6 AM on the
20th of the month.
And that day, it took 134
minutes to do our commute.
That's what this is telling me.
Or here, it's saying,
on this day,
let's go blue,
I left around 1030.
It was the 17th of the month,
and it took 59 minutes to get to
work.
That's how you interpret the
original data points.
And then our model looks like a
plane with a different slope in
each direction.
And the steepness in each
direction
is determined by those new W's
that we found.
There's a W that tells us how
steep it is in this direction
and another one that tells us
how steep it is in this
direction.
Okay?
So the model looks like a plane
in three dimensions.
What if we added another
feature?
How would we visualize the
model?
Well we would stop being able to
because we would have like some
three-dimensional thing in four
dimensions, right? Whereas this
model it looks like a
two-dimensional slice of three
dimensions.
So we wouldn't be able to
visualize it any further, but
it's good to know the geometry
of the situation.
Are we clear on why this model
would look like a plane? And
again, this is the kind of thing
we're going to study quite a bit
more for the rest of the
semester.
Seem reasonable?
OK.
All right.
Now, how do we find these
optimal w's?
How do we go about finding these
I have three parameters now.
How do I find w0 star, w1 star,
and w2 star? How do I try and do
that?
Yeah.
Maybe you do the same thing,
like with derivatives?
Yeah, same thing.
So let's copy this.
I'm going to follow that same
three-step modeling recipe of
choosing a model.
Here's the model.
Choosing a loss function.
Let's just stick with squared
loss because it's easy.
And then, or not easy, but
familiar.
And then minimize
average loss once again.
where we choose a model,
choose a loss function.
And minimize,
let's kind of mess here.
Now the question is, what does
average loss look like here?
Well,
I don't know why that happened.
Like every other average we've
seen,
somewhere in here there's going
to be a 1 over n times the sum.
If we're using squared loss,
it's going to be yi minus our
prediction squared.
It's just that our prediction
now,
let's make this a little
smaller,
looks like this.
How many input variables does
this function have?
This is, once again, just mean
squared error.
But how many input variables
would I say this has?
I don't know.
Yeah, three.
Good.
W0, W1, and W2.
Now, how do I find the optimal
w's here?
Well,
one thing I could do is I could
take the partial derivatives of
this mean squared error function
with respect to w0,
w1, and w2
and solve where they're all
equal to 0.
But I guess the short answer is
that taking partial derivatives
will get messy.
And then what if I introduced
another input variable and thus
another parameter?
Then I need to take four partial
derivatives, and each one would
involve all four variables.
And solving for where all four
partial derivatives is equal to
zero will get complicated.
So what would be nice is if we
could come up with one recipe
that tells us what the optimal
w's are supposed to be, no
matter how many parameters we
have.
So we don't need to re-follow
these steps differently
depending on if we have three
parameters, which would be if we
had two input variables,
or 17 parameters, which would be
if we had 16 input variables.
It would be nice if we could
just come up with one way of
saying,
here are the optimal parameters,
plug in your data set, and it
will tell you what they're
supposed to be.
I don't care how many features
you have.
And linear algebra will be the
tool that gets us there.
The short answer is,
over the next month or month and
a half we are going to define
what's called a parameter
vector, in which these w's,
where there are three right now,
w0, w1, w2, but eventually a w3,
w4, all the way through wd,
which will be our placeholder
for the number of features we
use,
all of those are wrapped in one
parameter vector.
And what we will be able to do
is express mean squared error in
terms of these objects that are
nice placeholders that
don't require you to explicitly
enumerate how many features you
have and redo the math every
time.
We can come up with one general
solution that allows us to use
as many features as we want.
But to work there,
we're going to have to introduce
a lot of ideas from linear
algebra.
But everything we're about to do
over the next month,
while it may seem disconnected
from this goal, it is all in
service of coming back to this
question.
So at some point,
it'll be after midterm one,
before midterm two,
we're going to revisit this
problem exactly and use linear
algebra to find these optimal
w's.
And by the way, one of the cool
things of how this is set up is
that when we use the linear
algebra solution to find the
optimal parameters,
it will also equal the other
formulas we found before.
So even in the case where we
just had one input variable And
we did the partial derivative
math ourselves.
So the linear algebra solution
we find in about a month will
match, in the case where you
just have one input variable,
the solutions that we just saw,
including the ones that involve
the correlation coefficient.
So that's a roadmap of where we
are heading
and why we kind of need tools
from linear algebra to move any
further.
Does that sound OK? All right,
so we're convinced why linear
algebra is necessary at this
point.
Okay,
so this is a good time to take
attendance before we start
getting into linear algebra.
It's 11.14,
we'll start again at 11.18,
but in the meantime,
log into attendance.
And once again, where you find
that is you go to the course
website and click this
attendance form at the top
right.
We'll start again at 11-18.
I think we're used to one that
can do it.
See,
my thing is that I've been doing
it for four years, and I'm not
going to do it right now.
Oh, there's a black book we got
now.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm really thinking the same
thing.
Everyone check
in.
Dedicated
the one
I don't think it is
I don't
know because I won't mess it
up.
Okay.
OK,
let's get started now that we
know where we are going to end
up with our study of linear
algebra.
Let's start with the basics of
vector.
I'm going to define a vector as
being
an ordered list of numbers.
I'll comment on what ordered
means in just a second.
But here is the notation we will
use for vectors in this class.
We will write them as columns in
which the numbers are written on
top of each other.
So for example,
3, negative 1,
2,
that's a vector.
negative 1, 3,
that's a different vector.
That's what I mean by ordered.
The order matters.
There are objects in math, like
a set, for example,
in which order doesn't matter,
but in a vector it does.
The variables I will use to
denote vectors will always be
letters with this arrow on top.
And as you will see over the
next few lectures,
we are going to get into,
or we are going to see
expressions and formulas that
involve numbers,
vectors,
matrices,
functions, There's lots of
things.
And it'll be important to keep
track of what type of object the
thing we are looking at is.
That'll be a common question you
are asked.
Is this a vector?
Is this a number?
Is this a matrix?
And one of the ways that we will
keep track of our bookkeeping is
by drawing these arrows
on top of a vector.
So if I say this first one is v,
the second one is w,
the fact that these vectors are
ordered
means that v and w are not the
same vector, okay?
Now both of these vectors have
three things in them, so I'm
gonna say they have three
components or elements.
I am NOT,
and this is where we have to
disassociate from how we think
of things in programming,
I am NOT going to say their
length is three,
do not say that,
okay?
Their length is measured using
geometry and we're gonna look at
that in just a second,
okay? This is where,
you know, if these were stored
as an array in Python,
Python would tell you that its
length is three, but
mathematically that's not what
its length is.
But the fact that V and W both
have three elements is often
denoted notationally in the
following way.
How do I make sense of this?
I have v.
What does this symbol mean?
In,
right?
And what does the second symbol
mean?
Anyone know?
Yeah.
The real number is cubed?
Yeah, it's not quite cubed.
But the way you should think of
this is that v is in the set of
vectors
who have three components,
all of which are real numbers.
So you should think of this set,
which I would call r3,
as being the set of vectors with
three numbers in them,
all of which are real numbers.
You could imagine there exists a
z3,
which is the set of vectors with
three integer components.
And sort of like in some
discrete math and cryptography
settings, you may work with
that.
But for us, all of our vectors
will involve real numbers.
And so the way you will
pronounce this,
and maybe I can just write this
down here,
is that v is in R3,
and R3 is the set of
vectors
with three real number
components.
W is also in R3 here.
Sound reasonable?
Okay good.
Because starting today and in
your like tomorrow's lab and the
following homework there's gonna
be a lot of notation thrown at
you and part of what we're
training you to do here is to be
able to look at new foreign math
that you haven't seen before
with new notation and make sense
of it.
So some of this is like a
grammar exercise.
Now, this is great.
We have two examples of vectors
that are in R3.
But in general,
the placeholder that I'm going
to use for the number of things
in a vector
is what? If you had to guess
based on the choices I've made
this semester of the variables
to use,
what do you think the
placeholder will be for the
number of things in a vector?
What is a natural choice? Emma,
N, yeah.
I'm trying to tie all of this
back to the setting in which we
have N data points.
And so eventually, we will make
that connection clear.
But N will be our placeholder
for the number of things in a
vector.
So Rn is like the general
template for the universe
vectors living.
And often, when defining
formulas or operations that
vectors in Rn support,
we will say that the elements in
this vector are v1 through
vn.
Here,
each vi is a scalar.
Can someone remind me what a
scalar is?
Yeah.
I think you're getting a little
into the definition of a vector.
What is just a scalar?
Just exactly, just one number.
So scalar and number really mean
the same thing.
It's just that in the context of
when you're dealing with vectors
we use the word scalar to
emphasize is that a scalar is
one number, a vector is a
collection of numbers, OK?
So here, the vi's are scalars.
But in another context,
vi could be a vector.
But if it were a vector,
how would I write it
differently?
If Vi was a vector,
it would have an arrow on it.
That's why it's important to
keep our notation straight.
So you can imagine either the
end of today or on Thursday,
I will define an operation that
takes in an arbitrary number of
vectors.
And I'm going to need to think
of a new placeholder number for
that.
Here I have just one vector v,
and I'm saying it has n things
in it.
But what if I have,
I don't know how many vectors I
have, but I have just some
general number of vectors.
I need another placeholder for
that.
And that formula will involve
vectors v1, v2, v3.
And then those will be vectors.
But for now,
if there's no arrow on top,
they're scalars.
Questions with our notation so
far?
I'm OK?
All right.
So the first natural thing to
get into before we look at
operations with vectors is to
readdress that point I made
about the length of a vector,
okay?
To illustrate, why don't we use
the vector u, and I'm gonna draw
this in orange,
3, 1.
A tiny detail that I don't think
anyone really cares about, but
it's important to me, is that if
you look at the course notes in
chapter 3,
every vector u is always orange
and every vector v is always
blue, but I use the same orange
and blue that my iPad notability
or GoodNotes uses as well.
So if you, like, took a
screenshot and looked at this
orange versus the notes orange,
it's the same.
This blue and the notes blue is
also the same.
No one really cares, but it's
good to have attention to
detail.
How might we visualize this
vector u?
If you've seen this before,
what's the most natural way to
visualize this vector u?
Yeah?
You can make 3 the x-axis and
then 1 on the y-axis.
Exactly.
The way to think about this is
that this is a vector that moves
three units to the right, or
three on the x-axis,
and one unit up.
Another way of thinking about
this is that it's the vector who
points from the origin, which is
the point zero zero,
to the point
three comma one.
Now vectors do not have a fixed
position,
okay?
So that is the vector u,
but that's not the only place
you could draw u.
And this is also u.
So the default way you should
think of a vector is as being an
arrow from the origin
to the point that corresponds to
the vector's components.
That's the default way to think
about it.
But a vector is not forced to
live anywhere, so depending on
the operation we're looking at,
we may draw the vector as
starting somewhere else.
Do we agree?
Okay.
And actually,
I'll make a new slide for
length.
The point that I was trying to
make here is a little different,
which is that vectors You have
no fixed
position.
Now back to the other point,
which is measuring the length of
a vector,
what is the most natural way to
measure the length of this
vector u?
Yeah, Bella.
You can use the distance
formula.
Yeah, or the Pythagorean
theorem,
our good old friend, Which says
that this vector
Looks like the hypotenuse of a
right-angled triangle whose legs
have lengths three and one
What does the Pythagorean
theorem tell us?
It tells us the length of u is
the square root of 3 squared
plus 1 squared
Which is the square root of 10?
Sound familiar?
Okay
The notation we will use for the
length of a vector is this.
These double vertical bars.
In some other classes, they may
just use a single vertical bar,
but I like using the double
vertical bars to emphasize that
this is not the same as the
absolute value of a number.
It's like a different operation,
and it's measuring the length of
a vector.
Now, there are lots of other
names that this length goes by,
there's length,
magnitude,
and norm.
These all refer to the same
idea.
And magnitude may be one that
you're familiar with from
physics class, because there
they will have defined a vector
as being an object with a
magnitude and a direction.
This may be familiar.
And the direction of a vector is
something we're going to talk
about more on Thursday.
OK,
these all refer to the same
thing.
Now,
let me comment on the idea of a
norm here.
What we're using here is one way
of measuring how long a vector
is,
which is using the Pythagorean
theorem,
which
we've established follows rules
of geometry that we're familiar
with.
It is not the only way we could
have measured the length of this
vector.
What is another way you could
have measured the length of this
vector?
It would be a different formula,
not equal to, And it wouldn't
give you the square root of 10.
But it would be like there's an
alternative way of measuring how
long this vector is.
Anyone think of one, or have you
seen one before?
Another way you could measure
the length of a vector is using
what's called its Manhattan
distance,
which is counting the number of
units you have to move left and
right plus the number of units
you have to move up and down to
get from the end of the vector,
the beginning of the vector to
the end.
So here, that would be 3 plus 1,
which is 4.
Why is it called Manhattan
distance? Well, if you've been
to New York, you know.
And most of it, the streets are
organized like a nice grid.
And to get between one point and
another point, you have to walk
left and right and then walk up
and down.
That's what this is named after.
That's one way.
There are several other ways you
could
measure the length of a vector.
And if you look at chapter 3.2,
it describes other
ways of measuring length.
The fact that this is using the
regular Pythagorean theorem way,
sometimes to make that super
clear, we will write a subscript
2 here.
And all that means is that these
individual components are being
squared.
But this is the default way.
If we don't give any more
details on how we are measuring
the length, it is by using the
Pythagorean theorem.
But wait, you may say.
This is the Pythagorean theorem
that you've heard of only works
in two dimensions.
What about vectors with three
numbers or four numbers or five
numbers?
I want you to guess how the
formula extends, But at least in
three dimensions,
we can draw another visual.
What I've drawn here in pink is
the vector 6,
negative 2,
3.
And what I've done here is I've
given,
as an expression, the most
natural extension of the length
formula to a vector with three
things in it.
It's the square root of the sum
of the numbers in it
squared.
Do you agree that that's like a
natural extension of the
Pythagorean theorem?
OK.
The fact that I have a negative
2 there,
it could have been positive 2,
it doesn't matter.
It's just easier to define the
formula in terms of the
components themselves.
But why does this measure the
length of this vector, 6,
negative 2, 3?
OK.
The cop-out answer would be,
because I said it is, because
that's the definition.
But we can think about this
geometrically as well.
So if you play around with this
picture, What you'll notice is
that there are two right angle
triangles at play here.
If I take this bird's eye view
where I don't have any depth
perception, I can't look at
height here, I have this first
right angle triangle.
One of its legs has a length of
six and the other has a length
of two.
And notice six and two, these
lengths are coming from the x
and y axis coordinates of the
vector six, negative two, and
three,
right? This 2,
the 2 that's running
horizontally on the page here,
is going from the point 0,
0, 0 in 3D to 0, negative 2, 0.
But it still has a length of 2.
And the taller leg has a length
of 6.
Do we see where the numbers 2
and 6 are coming from in the
context of 6, negative 2, and 3?
So this right angle triangle,
the one that's in this shaded
blue here, it has a hypotenuse.
And what is the length of its
hypotenuse?
What is the length of the
hypotenuse of the right angle
triangle we're looking at?
The blue one.
Yeah, that's that one.
Square root of 40.
Square root of 40, right? We
just apply the Pythagorean
theorem
to a right angle triangle whose
side lengths are 2 and 6.
So now we've got the hypotenuse
of this blue triangle is square
root of 40.
Now we're going to rotate here
and say,
OK,
forget about that one.
Now we've got another right
angle triangle.
And what are the side length
legs here, are the legs of the
side lengths here,
the lengths of the side lengths.
What are those?
The two perpendicular legs here,
what are their lengths?
Yeah? Square root of 40 and 3.
Yeah.
The longer leg here is the
square root of 4, which is the
hypotenuse of the first triangle
we saw.
Do we see that?
This leg that's labeled H behind
the pink wall here.
That's square root of 40, and
the height is 3.
And so what is the overall
length? Well, it's the square
root of 40 plus 3 squared,
which is the square root of 49,
which is 7.
If we just unwrap that formula,
how did we get the 40 under the
square root?
Well, it was just 2 squared plus
6 squared.
So the overall length is just
the square root of 2 squared
plus 6 squared plus 3 squared,
which is the square root of the
sum of the squares of the
components,
which is what we started with.
So do we see how the length of
this vector w
is really just the square root
of the sum of the squares of the
components?
Square root of 6 squared plus
negative 2 squared plus 3
squared.
After class, I want you to come
to this picture and play around
with it and make sense of it.
When we start thinking in three
dimensions, it can be hard to
wrap your head around what's
going on.
And it would be easy to just
say, like, all right, well,
here's the definition of the
length.
Here's what it said in the
textbook.
So I'm giving it to you.
But I want you to understand
where these things come from.
So this gives us a way of
defining
the length of a vector in Rn.
Can someone tell me what that
formula would look like?
The length of a vector in Rn.
Yeah, Allison.
Square root of the sum of i
equals 1 to n
of Vi squared.
Good.
Remember, the default
placeholder for the ith element
in a vector is Vi.
So this would be the square root
of the sum of Vi squared.
And if I write that without
summation notation, it's going
to look like V1 squared plus V2
squared plus through
vn squared,
OK?
And like I said, sometimes this
is called the L2 norm,
which is the default.
But chapter 3.2
tells you about some of the
other norms, like the L1 norm,
for example.
OK,
questions with the length of a
vector so far?
Seem OK?
Seem reasonable?
OK.
So there are two key operations
that vectors support.
You can add them,
and you can multiply them by a
scalar.
Notice I'm prefacing my
definition of multiplication
here with scalar, scalar
multiplication.
So what this will tell us how to
do
is multiply a vector by a single
number.
It turns out the idea of
multiplying a vector,
there's lots of ways you can do
it.
And next class, we will see ways
that you could multiply a vector
with another.
But it doesn't necessarily work
the way that you think it would.
OK,
so I want to start today by
introducing addition
and scalar multiplication.
OK,
let's start with addition.
Suppose I have two vectors,
u and v,
and both are in Rn.
What is the practical meaning of
this?
Why am I starting off by saying
They have the same number of
dimensions.
Yeah,
they have the same number of
components.
This is an important disclaimer
to start with, because as you
will see, it only makes sense to
add vectors when they both have
the same number of things in
them.
They both have five things, they
both have two things, they both
have three things.
Now, let's suppose I add u and
v.
The result
is a new vector.
But what is in that new vector?
Anyone know?
So you have to guess how this
works.
If you add vectors u and v,
what What are the components of
the new vector u plus v?
u1 plus v1.
Good.
The components get added up
element-wise.
So the first component of the
new vector
will be the first thing in u
plus the first thing in v.
The second thing in the new
vector
will be the second thing in u
plus the second thing in v.
And the last thing in the new
vector will be the last thing in
u plus the last thing in v.
This definition tells you that u
plus v is also equal to some
other operation.
What's it also equal to?
It may seem like a little
pedantic or
obvious,
but it's important for us to
state this.
Yes, it's also equal to v plus
u.
Now you may be saying like yeah,
obviously u plus v equals v plus
u That's like grade 2 math
But the reason it's important to
spell this out here is because
soon we will see operations
where this is no longer the case
Up until now in your sort of
math
You're like journey of learning
math almost every operation
worked both ways I guess there's
one that doesn't, which is
division.
2 divided by 3 is not the same
as 3 divided by 2.
But that feels a little more
intuitive to us.
Addition does work both ways.
And what is actually the term
for this?
Vector addition is what?
Commutative.
Commutative,
the property is called
commutativity,
is one of those weird words that
you've heard of in math.
There's also associativity,
distributivity.
To me,
whether something is commutative
is the most important of those
because, as I said,
we will soon see operations
where they are no longer
commutative when you would
assume that they are.
The way that I remember that
this is what commutative refers
to is that it sort of relates to
our running example in the
class.
When you commute to work, you
also go back.
So like going there and coming
back should be the same so like
u plus v and v plus u should be
the same
They didn't put me in charge of
naming things I'm just trying to
help you understand so that's
how I think of it Okay,
so how do we visualize vector
addition?
To illustrate
I'll draw the vector u 3 1 and
we'll use v being 4 negative 6
Here's how I want you to think
of vector addition
Sure, mathematically,
what we've just discussed is
that the resulting vector of u
plus v, since the first
component of u is 3 and the
first of v is 4,
the first of u plus v will be 7,
and the second component will be
negative 5, which comes from 1
plus negative 6.
That's all good.
But I want us to think about
what this actually looks like.
Now,
the way we're going to visualize
this is we're going to start
by drawing the vector u from the
origin.
Then I'm going to draw v not
from the origin, but starting at
the tip of u.
The end of the arrow is called
the tip,
the pointy part,
and the other part is called the
tail.
I'm gonna draw V which is gonna
go four units to the right and
six units down
Starting at you
It's not a not to scale
Actually, let me try and draw it
a little more to scale so you're
convinced of the result sure
Where does u plus v enter the
picture?
It is the result you get when
you connect the origin to the
tip of v,
when v is drawn starting at the
tip of u.
That is,
u plus v is this vector.
And this technique of
visualizing the addition is
called tip to tail.
So this shows me how I arrive at
u plus v,
starting with u and v.
The way that I like thinking of
this is that I'm using u and v
as building blocks to produce a
new vector.
It's like you're playing with
Legos.
Here's one Lego, here's another,
I put them together, I got a new
one.
Okay?
But since this is commutative,
it should also be the case that
if I started with v and then
tacked on u to it, I should end
up at the same place.
The names, u and v, are just
placeholders for these objects.
So if I instead start with v at
the origin,
I'll try and copy my exact v.
There we go.
And then draw u,
well,
I should end up with the same
vector.
And do I?
Indeed, I do.
Well, OK, let's not copy it,
because the annotation is in the
wrong place.
But
I
do end up with the same vector,
which is another way of
visualizing why this operation
is commutative.
We agree that these are the same
vector?
The purple ones?
My ability to draw a sign?
Is this 2D?
This is in 2D right now.
But the operation works the same
whether each vector,
whether we're dealing with
vectors in R2 or R3 or R
whatever.
It all works the same way.
And if you want to see some
examples of the addition working
in R3,
take a look at chapter 3.1.
We have a few of those plotted
out.
So that's vector addition.
Questions so far?
Let me really quickly tell you
about the other operation
because you'll need a little bit
of this
for tomorrow's lab.
Scalar multiplication involves
taking a vector v,
which is equal to, say,
v1, v2 through vn, and
multiplying it by a
scalar,
c,
where c is just a real number
while v
is a vector.
with n things in it.
So notice here,
I didn't write my orange u with
a vector hat on it.
There's just one vector involved
here.
And what I'm saying is that if
you multiply that vector by a
real number,
c,
the result is that it multiplies
every one of these components
by that same c.
So you can think of this as
keeping the direction of the
vector the same,
but changing what about it?
What does this do?
Yeah?
Yeah, what this does is it
changes the length.
If I multiply v by 2,
it doubles its length.
If I multiply it by negative 2,
what happens?
If you had to guess.
Yeah.
Yeah, flips the direction and
also multiplies its length by 2.
So to visualize what that looks
like,
if this is that vector u from
before,
3, 1,
what is 2u?
Well, it's gonna be this vector.
And what is negative 1 third u?
Well it's gonna be this vector.
So the negative sign flips a
direction and
the absolute value of the scalar
changes the length.
Now 2u looks like this.
What does 3u look like?
Well kind of roughly the same
thing it would just be off my
page.
What does negative 3u look like?
It'd be something like this.
What does pi times u look like?
I don't know, something like
that.
What does 0.4
times u look like? Something
like that.
So all of these scalar multiples
of u
is an important observation
here.
What do you notice about them?
All scalar multiples of u,
what is true about them?
That is true.
They all have the same slope, or
they all point in sort of
roughly the same direction.
But geometrically, how would I
sort of say that?
Yeah?
Yeah, that's sort of another way
of saying they all have the same
slope.
And I think you both have the
right observation, which is that
they all live on the same line.
OK,
so if I think of the set of all
scalar multiples of u,
they all live on this one line,
which has one slope,
right?
So they're all parallel to each
other.
It's not quite accurate to say
they all point in the same
direction, because the positive
scalar multiples go that way,
and the negative scalar
multiples go that way, but they
all still live on the same line.
So that's addition and scalar
multiplication.
When we come back,
we're going to look at what
happens when you do both of
these at the same time.
And so I'm just saying this
really quickly, because you're
going to start playing around
with this in lab tomorrow.
What I've done here is for two
vectors u and v, I've visualized
the new vector 3u minus 1 half
v.
And the idea here, when you do
both addition and scalar
multiplication,
you produce what's called a
linear combination of u and
v.
And a linear combination is the
most important operation we will
see this semester involving
vectors.
It's where we produce a new
vector by taking a little bit of
one plus a little bit of another
plus a little bit of another.
Here I visualize that for two
vectors in 2D, But I could take
a linear combination of 100
vectors in R17.
That's a reasonable thing to
need to do.
And that's the kind of thing
we're going to start to study.
OK?
But in tomorrow's lab, you'll
play around with what this looks
like.
Again, I have office hours after
this.
I just picked this up all the
time.
I didn't declare a major yet.
And since the first day of
class,
I'm going to do it.
Yes, I got an internship last
year as a sophomore at a company
called TechSmith.
Software testing internship,
that's like for the sophomores,
I think they'll take software
for years to do.
What kind of skills do you need
for that? on the skills like for
software testing they just want
to like attention to detail
basically
I'll excuse two of the four
missed lectures, so you can
still miss two.
Let me just sync the roster
right now.
Dude,
I was like,
I don't know, I start that shit.
I should get it done,
but I'll just keep pushing it
every year to reset,
so I think it's amazing.
Can you just ask it? I have
M-card access.
I'm missing two.
I'm about to get a little
milling.
There is a lot.
It's doable, but there's a lot.
The tricky thing is that- I
don't know,
I don't know,
because I- The stuff you just
heard talking about with
vectors, you technically don't
need to know anything we saw
from the first two weeks,
but the stuff from the first two
weeks is state trade, because
I'm gonna get that done anyway.
It'll be easy to,
if you just came today,
and you're gonna be in the
second half of today, you would
actually be able to follow all
of them.
I was supposed to get those last
two.
I did the trading,
it's like very important.
So like, it's possible to catch
up, yeah.
I'm curious, like, what made you
switch into the class last
minute? It would be out of your
way, let's hear it for now.
It's like the worst class time,
it's like noon,
it's like lunchtime,
we're getting Getting some food.
Do you all have glasses back to
back, or do you have some time
for before or after?
Not really much time.
I don't know.
What do you have to think?
Do you have to like sell? Do you
have to buy? notification
because I have to do this.
No, I think that's good.
I think I did a whole lot of job
with that.
Sure.
Just make sure you bring up the
video.